# ALI AZEM HABEEB ALRUBAEE. علي عازم حبيب الربيعي

BAGHDAD, AL-KARKH, AL-SAYDIA -10077 | 07516736973 | alialrubaee2011@gmail.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A multi-tasking communications engineer with 5 years of work experience working in sales, marketing and resource management engineering in a last position. My professional career was divided between an information technology engineer and its management, from preparing, setting up and operating, as well as working at the level of financial systems as an engineer responsible for managing data and creating reports

#### **EDUCATION**

2015 - 2016

**Bachelor**: Computer Communications Engineering Al-Mansour University College, Iraq - Baghdad - Al-Rusafa - Andalus Square

**SKILLS** 

- Project management
- Leadership ability
- Resource Management
- Network infrastructure administration
- Technical assistance
- New systems installation
- Sales and marketing
- Clients support

- Hiring and training
- E-Marketing
- Sales Management
- Oracle SQL analytics
- Systems monitoring
- Microsoft Exchange
- Microsoft Office
- Data Analysis

## WORK HISTORY

**HISTORY** May 2020- current

### Sales Engineer | ALRIBAL ALTHAHABI Company

- Receiving consumer orders and to carry out the preparation process.
- Make offers of discounts for the company and publish it on social media
- The high ability to listen to the complaints submitted by consumers, and to satisfy them, through the handling of those complaints.
- Checking new products and ensuring that they meet the required specifications
- Providing after-sales services and ensuring continuous provision of guarantees to customers

#### SEPTEMBER 2019- CURRENT (PART-TIME)

### Sales Management | Asala Al-Kawaz Trading Company

- Receiving consumer orders and sending them to the company for processing.
- Carrying out a sale transaction with the customer or consumer, and issuing a formal invoice documenting the sale.
- The high ability to listen to the complaints submitted by consumers, and to satisfy them, through the handling of those complaints.
- Checking prices and granting discounts on sales according to the powers granted and in accordance with the discounts policy announced by the company's higher management

#### JANUARY 2019- AUGUST 2020 (PART-TIME)

#### SYSTEM SUPPORT ENGINEER | AL-DAR SOLUTION COMPANY

- Management the Information Operations and Field Operations Department.
- Follow-up of business progress in the customer service department and check the information contained in the KYC form by clients before opening their accounts from individuals and companies.
- Make all sections and branches in constant contact

- Collaborate with employees to solve clients' problems and their own operations
- Support the clients for POS devices.
- Preparing reports on customers, their balances and POS details.
- POS termination process.
- POS performance update monthly
- clients commission report
- Manage core-bank system (IMAL) application
- Csm (core system management whose work relates to the main branch and all the processes associated with customers)
- Csm admin, sads)
- Make reporting using jasper soft
- End of day ,end of month , end of year operation using mts application
- Oracle SQL create and modify reports of core bank system

#### JANUARY 2019- MAY 2020

# **SENIOR INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY ENGINEER** | Ameen Al-Iraq Islamic Bank | Baghdad, AL-Rusafa.

As a Senior Information Technology Engineer in the Ameen Al-Iraq Bank, and since the Ameen Al-Iraq is a new bank, my duties were to put all my knowledge in this position to make everything go on the right track, and my responsibilities were as the following:

- 1. Manage Helpdesk section in the bank and that include (make the section budget and the section annul plan and to write the section roles and polices, etc. ...).
- 2. check and validation KYC form
- 3. Reviewing all incoming requests and deciding on the priority of tasks and distribution of these tasks to the Helpdesk team.
- 4. Maintain bank devices and that's include (Switches, Routers, Firewalls, Access Point, Servers, Access control, computers, etc...).
- 5. Manage the IT stock (computers, spare parts and consumable).
- 6. provide regular performance and need assessment reports to the management
- 7. Train the new staff on office program.
- 8. In charge of install and setup all the application in the bank and that's include (core bank application, Microsoft office, etc.) for all the users.
- 9. During the period of work in the company, I became the head of the procurement committee for all departments

From supplying materials, devices, information technology, electrical materials and some building and decoration materials

Including an assessment of the items affected and giving permission to compensate them

#### key achievement:

- 1- submit an analytical-technical weekly report
- 2- install the new E-KYC system form customer serves department and AML department
- 2- Train bank employee how to use the new KYC system
- 3- Train over 30 employees on how to use the new technology and new application to use them in their work.
- 4-set annual work plan for help-desk section
- 5-work with my team to upgrade all the devices in the bank

# **INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY ENGINEER** | First Step Company | Baghdad, Al-Rusafa.

- Work on company projects in building banks My job was the IT division of the company Supplying and installing these banks with complete systems that include camera systems, internal phones, and preparing a complete Internet system in addition to fire alarms and audio and video devices
- Most of the work and activities in the projects: Prepared new laptops and desktops for deployment by installing proper software and operating systems
- Created scripts and batch services to run network, server and desktop routines
- Maintained security of organization's IT database by updating security protocols and performing backups
- Installed and configured IT systems, including local area networks and wide area networks
- Participated in all phases of system development life cycle, from requirements analysis through system implementation
- Managed installation, upgrade and deployment projects and provided on-site direction for network engineers
- Installed, configured, tested and maintained operating systems, system management tools
- During the period of work in the company, I became the head of the procurement committee for all departments
  - From supplying materials, devices, information technology, electrical materials and some building and decoration materials
  - Including an assessment of the items affected and giving permission to compensate them
- Contracting with external companies to work on projects

### The projects of the banks in which participated:

- 1. Arab Mashreq Bank
- 2. International Development Bank
- 3. Amin Iraq Islamic Bank
- 4. Al-Rabita Islamic Bank
- 5. Arab Islamic Bank

# TRAINING & WORKSHOP

- 1. ORACLE SQL 12c (Course)
- 2. CCNA R&S 200-125 (Certified)
- 3. Windows server 2012 R2 (Course)
- 4. Cyber security from salalem (Certified)
- 5. Twenty hours of Accounting Course from ABC (Certified)
- 6. Five hours of risk education (Certified)
- 7. Five hours Caring for clients in financial institutions (Certified)
- 8. Forty hours Business English course

From iTTi. (Course)
9. Thankful letter for the actual participation in the installation of the Core bank system